Another term you'll have to recognize for your exam is a portfolio.
Portfolios describe kind of the book if you will of all the investments that an organization can make
in projects and programs into some climbs into operations.
So portfolio management describes all of the things that we are invested in.
So if you think about your own personal portfolio with your stocks or savings or what have you that's
your Portfolio portfolio and an organization or a business contacts describes the investments that a
business has in itself.
And what I mean by that are the programs and the projects and operations.
So portfolio management then is led by a portfolio manager for the organization usually a senior level
executive that is managing.
Where in how do we invest in programs and projects.
So considerations to include here with portfolio management the scope what exactly will you be delivering
delivering for the organization.
So think of business now you change you moving from one state to a desired future state so what's changing
here.
Planning how we plan how we approach the work how we do it efficiently and effectively the management
of the program or the project.
Now in our context we're thinking of just projects but the reality is could be a program would also
fall into a portfolio.
What is SuccessFactors.
How do you know you're successful.
What about monitoring the project.
So how do you monitor it.
In particular how do you monitor risk or anything that could threaten the project's success.
Because the portfolio manager is going to want to know how are you going to be successful in what you
deliver as an investment.
So what we are investing in and how we deliver what's the return on investment.
So portfolios are all about maximizing return on investment.
So an organization has a portfolio and within that are the investments.
Here is what a portfolio might look like whether it's like this big circle here.
But at the center is the portfolio that we have these orange squares that represent the programs that
we talked about a little bit ago and they remember programs have projects within them.
Well a portfolio can have projects and programs.
It's possible that a portfolio would have only programs and programs would have projects more likely
a portfolio is going to have both.
And yes it's possible that a portfolio could have only projects but probably you're going to have both.
When you look at a typical portfolio portfolios or are interested in the oversight as we just talked
about the scope how do you manage change how are going to plan for success.
How are you going to manage it or who's going to manage that program or project what constitutes success
because we're what return on investment then how do you monitor that and part of that monitoring will
be communicating when you have variances are and things aren't going to play in.
And we'll talk about communications in chapter 10 in the Pemba the organizational portfolio another
way of looking at this.
You have the portfolio within the portfolio we have programs and we have projects of just what we talked
about.
But there's this other thing done here at the end that we could have a sub portfolio a sub portfolio
as part of the overall.
You mentioned a really huge organization like a government or a really massive business.
They might have a portfolio the amount of funds they can invest in the entire company and rather than
one person managing all of that they chunk it out by departments or lines of business or types of projects
and programs.
So you could have a sub portfolio and then the sub portfolio would have programs and projects as we
described.
And yes operations could be part of a portfolio but typically we're heard about programs and projects
but you could have operations in there.
All right great job.
Keep moving forward.